{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "One of the following sources of water may make up the major or sole source of water in desert animals such as camels:",
      "choices": [
        "Drinking water",
        "Metabolic water",
        "Water from river",
        "Water present in the feed",
        "Water from rain"
      ],
      "answer": "Metabolic water"
    },
    {
      "question": "The amount of water obtained from feedstuffs could be relatively high in:",
      "choices": [
        "Cereal",
        "Straw",
        "Alfalfa hay",
        "Lush grass",
        "Grass hay"
      ],
      "answer": "Lush grass"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following polysaccharides functions as energy storage in plants and animals, respectively?",
      "choices": [
        "Glycogen and starch",
        "Starch and cellulose",
        "Glycogen and cellulose",
        "Starch and glycogen",
        "Raffinose and glycogen"
      ],
      "answer": "Starch and glycogen"
    },
    {
      "question": "The most common hexose in polysaccharides than the rest is:",
      "choices": [
        "Fructose",
        "Galactose",
        "Sucrose",
        "Glucose",
        "Lactose"
      ],
      "answer": "Glucose"
    },
    {
      "question": "The polysaccharide most abundant in nature is:",
      "choices": [
        "Glucose",
        "Starch",
        "Cellulose",
        "Glycogen"
      ],
      "answer": "Cellulose"
    },
    {
      "question": "The disaccharide cellobiose is composed of the monosaccharide:",
      "choices": [
        "Glucose and galactose",
        "Glucose and raffinose",
        "Glucose and glucose",
        "Fructose and galactose"
      ],
      "answer": "Glucose and glucose"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following carbohydrates do not belong to oligosaccharides?",
      "choices": [
        "Lactose",
        "Cellobiose",
        "Raffinose",
        "Sucrose",
        "Cellulose"
      ],
      "answer": "Cellulose"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a metabolic role of carbohydrates?",
      "choices": [
        "Source of energy",
        "Energy reserve",
        "Synthesis of fat",
        "Synthesis of essential amino acids"
      ],
      "answer": "Synthesis of essential amino acids"
    },
    {
      "question": "The group of proteins which includes all enzymes, antigens, and those hormones which are protein is:",
      "choices": [
        "Fibrous protein",
        "Phosphoprotein",
        "Glycoprotein",
        "Globular protein",
        "Conjugated protein"
      ],
      "answer": "Globular protein"
    },
    {
      "question": "A conjugated protein that contains a pigment as a prosthetic group is:",
      "choices": [
        "Glycoprotein",
        "Lipoprotein",
        "Chromoprotein",
        "Phosphoprotein",
        "Urea"
      ],
      "answer": "Chromoprotein"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following amino acids are not synthesized in the body in sufficient amount and hence are required in the diet?",
      "choices": [
        "Methionine",
        "Lysine",
        "Glutamic acids",
        "Glycine",
        "A and B"
      ],
      "answer": "A and B"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following amino acids are synthesized in the body in sufficient amount?",
      "choices": [
        "Glycine",
        "Cysteine",
        "Glutamine",
        "Lysine",
        "All except D"
      ],
      "answer": "All except D"
    },
    {
      "question": "Birds excrete nitrogen in the form of:",
      "choices": [
        "Uric acid",
        "Propionic acid",
        "Ammonia",
        "Lactic acid",
        "Urea"
      ],
      "answer": "Uric acid"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following macromolecules is a simple lipid?",
      "choices": [
        "Waxes",
        "Glycolipids",
        "Phospholipids",
        "Fats and oils"
      ],
      "answer": "Fats and oils"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following fatty acids is not a polyunsaturated fatty acid?",
      "choices": [
        "Linoleic",
        "Oleic",
        "Linolenic",
        "Arachidonic"
      ],
      "answer": "Oleic"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following fatty acids has four double bonds?",
      "choices": [
        "Arachidonic",
        "Oleic",
        "Linolenic",
        "Palmitoleic"
      ],
      "answer": "Arachidonic"
    }
  ]}